dti.gov.ph 2018-10-12

# Privacy Policy

#### WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY

**Introduction**

The Department of Trade and Industry (DTI), through its Knowledge Management and Information Service (KMIS), maintains [www.dti.gov.ph](http://www.dti.gov.ph/ "Official DTI website"), which aims to provide information about the Department, its mandates, programs, and services.

As an agency of the government of the Republic of the Philippines, the website adheres to the [Government Website Template Design (GWTD) Guidelines](http://i.gov.ph/policies/signed/memorandum-circular-rules-regulations-migrating-gwhs-dost-ict-office/annex-c-government-website-template-design-gwtd-guidelines/ "Government Website Template Design \(GWTD\) Guidelines") prescribed by the Department of Information and Communications Technology (DICT), which highlights, among others, compliance with the Data Privacy Act of 2012 (Section 2.3.5) and recognizing the importance of improving user experience (Section 3).

**Data Collection and Use**

The website itself does not collect personal data that would identify a specific individual. However, as a means to gather feedback and improve services, the website incorporates three online surveys housed with Google Forms:

  1. The DTI Website Feedback form
  2. The DTI e-Library form
  3. The Domestic Trade Exchange (DTEX) Trade Association Survey form

The type of data that are obtained include:

  1. Sex
  2. Age (within a given range)
  3. Occupation/field of specialization/sector

The non-personal data being collected using Google Forms is governed by the external website’s own privacy policy.

**Website Analytics**

Google Analytics is being used to track website performance. It gathers non-personal information from the browser whenever the site is visited. This may include the computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, browser version, pages visited, date and time of visit, and time spent on these pages, among others. These are reported through aggregated data that in no way will identify an individual.

The website itself does not maintain cookies and neither does it access third-party cookies from Google Analytics, which has its own strict privacy guidelines.

**Links to External Websites**

This website contains links to other websites – visitors are advised to take note of these sites’ respective privacy policy.

**Changes to this Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 2017, and will remain effective unless there is a revision, which will be effective immediately after being posted on this site. Users of this website may also provide feedback to this policy through the contact information provided below.

**Contact**

For feedback and other concerns about this policy, please contact the Knowledge Management and Information Service (KMIS) through email [kmis@dti.gov.ph](mailto:kmis@dti.gov.ph).
